+62 811 62 0023 Jakarta, Indonesia arief25ramadhan@gmail.com

Arief Ramadhan

AI / Machine Learning Engineer

github.com/arief25ramadhan linkedin.com/in/arief25ramadhan

I am a visionary engineer with a master's degree in Robotics. I currently work at Nodeflux as an Artificial Intelligence (AI) Engineer and MindHope.id as the Co-founder/Engineer. I mentor AI interns and speak at AI-related events occasionally. My goal is to become an AI expert through research and development.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Robotics, University of Bristol 2018-2020

Graduated with Merit

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, Institut Teknologi Bandung

2013-2017

Jun 2020 — Sep 2020

Jakarta, Indonesia

2021

2020

Cumulative GPA: 3.16/4.0

SKILLS

Programming Languages Python, SQL, MarkDown

Tools Git, Linux, Docker, Azure Form Recognizer Frameworks Tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch, Paddlepaddle

Quantitative Research Image Processing, Computer Vision, Optical Character Recognition, Object Detection, Image Segmenta-

tion, AI Model Optimization

Communication English (Professional), Bahasa Indonesia (Native)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Artificial Intelligence Engineer Jan 2021 — Present Nodeflux Jakarta, Indonesia

• Create OCR Pipelines for multiple documents that have received > 450 thousands hit

- Achieve OCR accuracy of >95% for ID Card (KTP), Driver's License (SIM), and Tax Card (NPWP)
- · Build and train text detector, text recognizer, and segmentation model
- Research on Image Quality Assessment

Co-Founder/Engineer Jun 2021 — Present Jakarta, Indonesia MindHope.id

- Develop business model, customer avatar, and conduct competitor analysis
- Create timeline, Standard Operational Procedure of research process, and research proposal
- Design product requirements
- · Build a chatbot using Python and Rasa framework
- Deploy a chatbot using Google Cloud Platform's Virtual Machine

Artificial Intelligence Engineer

Telkom Indonesia

- Work in data science team in a B2B E-Commerce project
- · Learn and create a concept of recommendation engine
- Maintain and handle data using SQL
- Volunteer as a data collector of Covid-19 cases in Indonesia

Speaker: What Makes AI Essential in Our Future, ESQ Business School

Speaker: Sound Source Localization, Jakarta Machine Learning

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Al Mentor, Nodeflux	2022
Computer Vision Unit Leader, Supertype.Al	2020
Head of Logistic Division, Himpunan Mahasiswa Mesin	2015
Speaking Engagements	
Judge Panel: Compfest Al Innovation Challenge, University of Indonesia	2022
Speaker: How AI plays a Role in Our Lives Now and the Future, Universitas Buya Hamka	2021

PROJECTS

2nd Place MX Magazine Writing Competition, Indonesia

Article featured in the Mechanical Engineering Student's Magazine

Optical Character Recognition for ID Card, Driver's License, and Tax Card Jan 2021 — Present Nodeflux Jakarta, Indonesia • Create OCR Pipelines using PaddleOCR and Azure Form Recognizer. • Build and train text detector, text recognizer, and semantic segmentation model. • Create synthetic data, check data quality and label consistency using Fiftyone. • Use MLFlow for training reproducibility. **Histopathologic Cancer Detection** Mar 2020 — Apr 2020 Jakarta, Indonesia Personal • Final project for Udacity Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree • Build a Neural Network that detects tumors in medical scan images Transfer learning using the VGG-16 Imagenet model A Comparison of Neural Network Performance for Sound Source Localization Jan 2019 — Aug 2019 Master's Thesis Bristol, UK Design a binaural robot head using Solidworks Assemble the robot consisted of 3D printed part, servo motor, and microphone Collect and preprocess audio data using the assembled robot • Compare several Neural Network models to classify sound angle relative to the robot **COURSE CERTIFICATIONS** Hydranets: Monstrous Multi-Task Learning Techniques with PyTorch, Think Autonomous 2022 Neural Optimization: Elite Tactics to Build Production-Ready Algorithms with PyTorch, Think Autonomous 2022 **Computer Vision Engineer Nanodegree**, *Udacity* 2020 Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree, Udacity 2020 **Deep Learning Specialization**, Coursera 2019 **ACHIEVEMENTS** 3rd Place Facebook Developer Circle London Hackathon, London, UK 2019 8th Place Warstek Science Writing Competition, Indonesia 2018 Out of 150+ Participants

2017